There are many monsters threatening humans.
有许多怪物 威胁着人类
Many brave adventurers stepped forward bravely.
挺身而出的是 众多勇敢的冒险家
And I,
而我
Alvin, is one of them.
埃尔文就是其中一位
Forming a party with the healer Carla,
与僧侣卡菈组队
let's continue the adventure today.
今天也持续冒险旅程
DON'T HURT ME, MY HEALER
(这个僧侣有够烦)
THE TITLE "THE SECOND PART OF "WHAT'S THIS STORY" MAKES ANNA AND RYOKO,"
(此次的标题) ("这是什么故事"的第二篇)
WHO AREN'T IN THE ORIGINAL WORK "DON'T HURT ME, MY HEALER", ACTIVE IN THE ANIMATION. IT'S EXCITING. THANK YOU FOR
(让"这个僧侣有够烦"原著中) (没登场的安娜和灵子在动画中活跃 真的很令人高兴)
MAKING UP THE INSUFFICIENT PART OF THE ORIGINAL WORK IN THE ANIMATION. ON THE OTHER HAND, A POPULAR ANIMATION APPEARED
(另外也很感谢动画补足了原著中交代不足的部分) (另一方面这集出现了某个国民人气动画哏)
IN THIS EPISODE. I BELIEVE EVERYONE UNDERSTANDS WITHOUT EXPLAINING IT. "OPEN IT IF YOU DARE. COME ON."
(当然不必在此说明大家都懂) (有种打开看看 诺)
"IN THOSE DAYS, INSTEAD OF USING A DIGITAL BRUSH," This is... a treasure box, right?
(但今非昔比当年可不是用数位画笔) 这是…宝箱吧
"REAL DRAWING TOOLS WERE USED TO DRAW OUTLINES AND COLOUR." Right.
(而是用真正的绘图工具一笔一笔绘出轮廓涂上颜色) 是啊
"IT MAY BE GOOD TO LET PEOPLE KNOW THAT THE STAFF BACK THEN REALLY WORKED HARD AND" But...
(能借此让众人知道当年的工作人员为了动画) 可是…
"HAD BEEN PASSIONATE ABOUT ANIMATION. THAT'S EPISODE 11." I didn't expect to be provoked by the treasure box one day.
(真是燃烧热情费尽辛劳或许也算是一件好事的第十一话) 没想到 会有被宝箱挑衅的一天
"OPEN IT IF YOU DARE. COME ON." No, I was provoked by the plate.
(有种打开看看 诺) 不 是被牌子挑衅了
That's great. It's a rare experience.
不错啊 很少有这种遭遇哦
It really annoys me.
真令人不爽
The treasure box is in the middle of the main road. There's obviously something wrong.
宝箱放在大马路中央 明显有问题吧
It's strange indeed.
的确很奇怪
Okay. Let's open it.
好 打开看看吧
That's the strange point.
这就是奇怪的点吧
Don't we open it?
不打开吗
We're adventurers. We can't have any leftovers. So we should open it.
我们是冒险家 吃饭不能有剩 所以应该要打开吧
Go pick up the remaining dishes.
去捡菜尾吧你
Which fool would particularly open such an obviously doubtful treasure box?
哪个笨蛋会特别去打开 这么明显有问题的宝箱
Maybe it's just you who'd open it, you fool.
搞不好只能钓你你这个笨蛋吧
You're too much. You just called me a fool, didn't you?
过分 你刚才骂我笨蛋吧
Hold on. It could be alpaca.
等等 可能是草泥马
You just called me an alpaca, didn't you?
你刚才骂我草泥马对吧
I said you're a fool.
我说你是笨蛋
You said fool...
你说笨蛋啊…
No matter how many times you ask me, I've said it.
不管你问几次 我就是说了
Do you mean stupidly cute when you said fool?
不过你说的笨蛋 是不是指笨的可爱
I'll give you one more chance.
再给你一次机会
No.
不是
Please.
拜托啦
I'm begging you.
我求你啦
What are you doing? Don't pull! Let go of it!
你干嘛 不要拉 放手
-Both of you. -What's wrong?
-两位 -干嘛
I've just seen it with thief skills.
我刚才用盗贼技能看过了
There seems to be no trap in the treasure box.
宝箱里好像没有陷阱
But it's obviously suspicious.
可是 明显很可疑耶
Was it made obviously on purpose? No one dares to open it instead.
会不会是故意弄得很明显 反而没有人敢打开
I'm not sure why, but there may be treasure in it.
虽然不清楚原因 但里面可能真的有宝物哦
No. How could it be...
不 怎么可能…
But there's a possibility of one in ten thousand.
不过也是有万分之一的可能性
Open the treasure box when you see it...
看到宝箱就要打开…
Open it. Open it. Open it.
打开 打开 打开
-Bristle brush. Bristle brush. Bristle brush. -Don't urge me by beating time.
-鬃刷 鬃刷 鬃刷 -不要打拍子催促
Since there's no trap, let's open it.
既然没有陷阱 那就打开吧
I guess it's just a prank.
我猜这只是恶作剧
When we open it and see nothing, we'll rejoice too soon.
打开后看到空无一物 空欢喜一场
It's possible.
有可能
Bristle brush...
鬃刷…
Wait a minute.
等一下
There's no trap in the treasure box...
宝箱里虽然没有陷阱…
But the trap could be around the treasure box. So be careful.
但陷阱有可能在宝箱周围 所以请小心哦
Too late.
慢了一步
As expected of one of Alvin's 18 martial arts,
不愧是埃尔文的十八般武艺之一
falling into a hole.
掉入洞穴
Are... Are you all right?
你你你你没事吧
Are you hurt?
有没有受伤
What a special way of showing care.
你的关怀方式真特别
Can you come out?
出的来吗
Let me try.
我试试
I can't.
不行
I thought of something.
我想到一件事
What's it?
什么事
"THE TWO SPLIT UP TO COLLECT HERBS AND MOUNTAIN VEGETABLES" Altargaia is good at picking herbs and mountain vegetables.
(分开行动采药草和山菜的两人) 奥尔特盖亚擅长采药草和山菜吧
This is very effective for diarrhea.
这对腹泻很有效哦
We picked a lot.
摘了好多哦
Ryoko's storage skills are excellent.
灵子的收纳技能非常优秀
And I at least have thief skills.
而我至少也有盗贼技能
Carla is a cleric.
卡菈是圣职人员
This is open to question.
这有待商榷
-Objection. -Silence.
-我有异议 -肃静
Anyway, everyone has their own characteristics and skills.
总之每个人都有自己的特性和技能
Stop it.
够了
Meanwhile, you...
反观你…
Anna!
安娜
Stop saying that.
别说这些了
Please don't get rid of the soil on my head.
请不要在我头上拍土
Don't judge a person's value by whether he can be of help.
不以是否派得上用场 来判断一个人的价值
And are you standing on my cape?
还有你是不是站在我的披风上
And Mr. Alvin has many strong points.
而且 埃尔文先生 也是有很多优点的
Tell me about it.
说来听听
It's... It's that... Right?
就是…就是那个…对吧
That was vague.
语焉不详
That's not it.
不是的
You have too many strong points that I don't know what to say.
你的优点多到 我不知道该说什么才好
I counted slightly. You have about 200 million strong points.
我稍微数了一下 大概有两亿个优点
Nonsense. Probably not even one...
屁啦 八成一个都…
No. Two hundred million.
不 两亿
This is the unit that children use when they lie.
这是小朋友在说谎时才会使的单位
At least you say hundred.
你好歹说百吧
Hundred? You feel good about yourself.
百 自我感觉良好耶
That's right.
说的也是
Forget it. I don't have any strong points, anyway.
算了 反正我没什么优点
That's not true.
没这回事
Strong point one.
优点一
In case of emergency, your armour can be used for barbecue.
遇到紧急状况 你的盔甲能拿来烤肉
What on earth? What strong point is that?
什么鬼东西 这哪算我的优点
Strong point two.
优点二
Listen to me.
听我说
That's all?
没了吗
I've got it! How about this?
想到了 这个如何
It can be used to grill fish.
可以烤鱼
No more, right?
没了是吧
Carla, Carla. That's not it.
卡菈 卡菈 不是这样啦
Oh, I forgot the most important thing.
对哦 我忘记最重要的事了
Apply oil first.
要先抹油
Or it'll get burnt.
不然会烤焦的
The order doesn't matter!
顺序不重要啦
Why do you regard my equipment as a cooking tool? That's not right.
为什么一直拿我的装备 当作料理的工具 不是这样吧
You're talking about my strong points, aren't you?
现在是在说我的优点吧
Just say something like gentle at this time.
这种时候 随便说个温柔就好啦
What? Can even vegetables be grilled?
什么 连蔬菜都能烤吗
What a civilized good tool!
简直文明利器
Get rid of your earwax!
去清耳屎啦
Don't get too tired.
别太累了
What are you doing?
你在干嘛
How? Can you come out?
怎么样 能出来吗
You wish.
最好能出来啦
How weird.
真奇怪
Are you saying you're weird?
你说你很奇怪吗
Normally, when I say "Bang", the sapling will grow out of the ground.
照理说 在我"啪"的时候 树苗就会从地底下长出来
-Thump. You'll be pushed up. -So it's not a dream.
-咚 你就会被推上来 -原来不是梦
It seems that I really can't compare with the person concerned.
看来我果然比不上当事人
I sweat a lot.
流了好多汗
The person concerned?
当事人
Don't you know that? It's famous.
你不知道吗 很有名耶
I have no idea what you're talking about.
我完全不懂你在说什么
Carla is trying hard to help you.
卡菈很努力想帮你耶
You should be serious, too.
你也认真一点嘛
Well. I'm stuck. I can't move...
不 我卡很紧动不…
It seems that I can move.
好像 可以动了
-Look. -I'm sorry.
-看 -抱歉
Then I should be able to do it on my own.
接下来我应该能自己来了
Hang on a minute.
等一下
Let me help you.
我来帮你吧
Let. Me. Help. You.
我 来 帮 你
No, it's fine.
不 不用了
I should be able to come out if I try harder.
我再努力点应该能出来
No. Don't make a pointless struggle.
不 别做无谓的挣扎
No, I meant it.
不 我说的是真的
No, please feel free.
不不不 别客气
If you're not careful, your upper and lower bodies will be separated.
一个不小心 上下半身会分家哦
Leave it to me.
交给我吧
They won't be separated. I don't need it.
不会分家 不需要
No. Most likely, they'll be separated.
不不不 十之八九会分家
Look at the atmosphere, okay?
看一下气氛好吗
Carla must be trying to help you.
卡菈一定是想帮你的忙
How troublesome.
好麻烦
All right.
好吧
Carla, give me a hand.
卡菈 帮我一把吧
Of... Of course, no problem.
当 当然是没有的问题
Carla?
卡菈
All right. I usually give him a lot of trouble.
好 平常给他添了不少麻烦
Take this opportunity...
趁这个机会…
Do him a favour and make him willing to accept my trouble in the future.
卖他个人情 让他以后 都愿意接受我的麻烦
Good things never come too late. Hurry and ask me for help...
好事不宜迟 赶快拜托我帮忙…
I'm so dirty.
全身脏死了
Let's find a place to rinse.
找个地方冲洗一下吧
You tricked my mood!
你竟然玩弄我的心情
Anyway, you're probably thinking about unimportant things.
反正你八成在想些有的没的的吧
Devil, ghost animal, demon, heretic, evil wisdom king, evil emperor,
恶鬼 鬼畜 恶魔 邪教徒 邪道明王 邪道皇帝
-evil spirits, a man bewitched by darkness, -Well. Hold on.
-魑魅魍魉 被黑暗迷惑之人 -不 等等
-the Paladin of Light... -There's a good compliment!
-光之圣骑士 -混了一个不错的夸奖
These names are well fit for you. I'm so hesitant.
这些称呼都很适合你 好犹豫哦
Shameful Knight Parade.
羞耻的骑士游行
All right...
好…
Don't we open it?
不打开吗
The treasure box itself has no traps.
宝箱本身没有陷阱
That means if we don't open it, the treasure box will always be here.
也就是说不打开的话 宝箱就会一直在这
But there are many traps around it.
可是周围很多陷阱吧
It means someone put the treasure box here with ill will.
就表示有人带着恶意 把宝箱放在这里
Then there's no need to open it. It was just a prank anyway.
那就没必要打开 反正就只是个恶作剧
You're scared.
你怕了
You want to leave early because you were caught in the boring trap, right?
因为中了无聊的陷阱 所以才想早点离开对吧
It's already over.
这件事已经结束了
I can do nothing with you.
真拿你没办法
It seems that our vanguard is a coward.
看来我们的前卫大人是个胆小鬼
All right. I'll open it for you.
好吧 我来帮你打开
Coward, just step back.
胆小鬼就退后吧
Although I don't expect anything from the treasure box,
虽然我对宝箱没什么期待
I don't know what ghosts and monsters will appear in it.
不知里面会出现什么牛鬼蛇神
Maybe it's just an ordinary snake
可能只是普通的蛇
or a powerful snake.
又或是厉害的蛇
No. Maybe it's an eight-headed and eight-tailed serpent.
不 搞不好是八岐大蛇
What are you doing?
你干嘛啦
I couldn't help myself...
不小心就…
Don't yell so loudly all of a sudden!
不要突然叫这么大声啦
I'm sorry.
抱歉嘛
I won't forgive you!
我绝不原谅你
Unforgivable. Resort to legal means.
不可原谅 使出诉诸法律之招数
There it appears. The profound meaning of ancient martial arts.
出现了 古代武术的奥义
You're doomed. I'll see you in court.
你完蛋了 我们法庭上见
Excuse me. Who are you?
请问你是哪位
Who am I?
我是哪位
I'm a mimic, Nakami.
我是模仿怪 内在啦
Nakami?
内在
How come?
怎么会这样
What's wrong?
怎么了
I've been in place since three days ago.
我从三天前就就位了
All I did was in vain.
这一切都白费了
I didn't mean that.
我没这个意思
You're too much. It's so poor.
过分 人家好可怜哦
Phoenix Hall of The Inhuman Temple.
不人道院凤凰堂
You just fell into a meaningless trap hole. It was a waste of time.
只掉进无意义的陷阱洞穴 浪费时间
I should be the interesting part.
好戏应该是我才对
Isn't there no trap?
不是没有陷阱吗
If I scare someone, I can level up smoothly.
如果吓到人的话 我就能顺利升级了
My trap detection doesn't respond to mimics.
我的陷阱探测功能对模仿怪没反应
I'm going to get a pay cut.
我要被处以减薪处分了
Anna, he's not sensible yet.
安娜 他还不懂事嘛
Are you listening to me?
你们有在听吗
Sorry, our newbie owes you.
抱歉 我们家新人害了你
He's not mature yet. Please forgive him.
他还不成熟 你就大人有大量吧
But as a cooking tool, he's an excellent tool.
不过 以料理用具来说 他是个优秀的工具哦
What kind of compliment is that?
这是哪门子的夸奖
And you seem to have mistaken it.
而且 你好像搞错咯
It was a rehearsal just now.
刚才那只是采排
A rehearsal?
采排
Of course.
那当然
Even well-known dancers
就算是很有名气的舞者
can't go on stage without rehearsal.
也不可能没采排就直接上场
Professionals should come on stage after rehearsal.
专业人是就是要认真采排后上场
It makes sense.
有道理
No wonder I find it strange.
难怪我觉得哪里怪怪的
So it was a rehearsal.
原来是采排啊
That's why he fell into the hole to check the condition of the hole.
所以才特地掉进洞穴里 检查洞穴的状况
That's right. Who would be so dull to fall into a hole like that?
也是啦 哪有人会迟钝到 掉进那种洞穴里
Right.
就是嘛
Not everyone is a dull adventurer newbie level 100.
又不是每个人都是 迟钝的冒险家新手等级一百
OPEN IT IF YOU DARE. COME ON.
(有种打开看看 诺)
Then it's a formal one.
那么 接下来就是正式的咯
Yes.
对
Okay. I'll show you my real terrifying power.
好 我也会让你们见识一下 我真正的吓人威力
I'll also show a surprising way that can't be compared just now, too.
我也会表现出 刚才不能相比的惊吓方式
I'm looking forward to it.
好期待哦
End it quickly, okay?
快点结束好吗
I can't wait for it.
我很期待哦
It's upside down.
反了反了
Okay. Let's start from where Carla walks to the treasure box.
好 从卡菈走向宝箱的地方开始
Six seconds before shooting.
开拍前6秒
Five, four, three...
5 4 3…
I didn't expect there was a treasure box here.
没想到这里有宝箱
Huh?
咦
She probably doesn't understand countdown.
她没大概不懂什么是倒数
How lucky.
太幸运了
I must have done a lot of good deeds.
一定是平常做了很多好事
All right. Let's open it.
好 马上打开来看看
I'm going to open it.
要开咯
Open it in three seconds.
倒数三秒就打开哦
Count down three seconds. Okay.
倒数三秒  好
-Ten, nine... -Starting from ten.
-10 9 -从10开始
Hold on. There may be a mimic in the treasure box.
等等 宝箱里搞不好有模仿怪
She's so sharp. She found it out.
好敏锐 被发现了
We would be in trouble.
这样就麻烦了
I heard that mimic is a terrifying monster.
我听说模仿怪是很可怕的魔物
It looks like an actual nightmare.
他的模样 就像实体化的恶梦
It has six arms and eight feet.
有六只手臂八只脚
There are many tentacles on its head.
头上还长了很多只触手
Even without the above features, at least it won't be a monster
就算没有以上特征 至少也不会是绘本中出现的
with an eye and a small horn that a child can deal with in a picture book.
一只眼睛 长着小小的角 那种小孩子能应付的魔物
There are no such silly monsters among mimics.
模仿怪里才没这种胡闹的魔怪
Even if it's one of them, its gesture is just an illusion.
就算在里面 他的姿态也只是个假象
Its original appearance is a horrible monster.
其原本样貌 是个恐怖的怪物
If it shows up here,
如果他在这里出现
it'll show an amazing and frightening gesture of terror and vigour.
一定会现出既惊人又吓人的 超恐怖又有魄力的姿态
I tremble with fear just by imagining it.
我光是想象就怕得发抖
But as an adventurer, I have to open the treasure box when I see it.
但是 身为冒险家 看到宝箱不能不打开
I'll open it even if the monster hides in the treasure box.
就算宝箱里躲的魔物 我也要打开
Namo...
南无…
It's locked.
上锁了
Lock of soul.
心灵之锁
My bone may have cracked.
骨头可能裂了
The worst case could be a fracture.
最惨的情况 可能骨折了
It's bloated. Does it hurt?
都种起来了 会痛吗
I took relieving herbs, so it doesn't hurt.
我吃了止痛药草 所以不痛
But it's a fortune in misfortune to get only a little hurt.
不过 只受这点伤 是不幸中的大幸了
It was frightening.
真是吓死人了
I didn't expect to meet a Cyclops.
没想到会遇上独眼怪
And she was changing her clothes.
而且 她正在换衣服
She hit without even asking.
问都不问就打了过来
Fortunately, I dodged at the critical moment.
还好我在紧要关头躲开了
Of course, she'd be angry as we saw her changing clothes.
被人看到正在换衣服当然会生气啊
She's a girl.
人家是少女呢
The fact that she's a girl scares me even more.
她是少女这件事 更是吓到我了
And this time, it was really Carla who saved me.
而且 这次真的是卡菈救了我
It would be terrible without Carla.
没有卡菈的话就惨了
Not at all. I did nothing...
哪有 我什么都…
Carla, don't be humble.
卡菈 别谦虚嘛
Well. Then...
这样啊 那…
Worship me.
快崇拜我
You'd better be humble.
你还是谦虚点
But it's all thanks to Carla...
不过确实是多亏了卡菈…
Are you all right?
你没事吧
My goodness. It hurts just by grazing it.
天啊 仅仅擦过就这么痛
Anyway, let's try to escape...
总之 我们想办法逃…
Carla.
卡菈
Stop there.
你给我站住
You fool, step back!
笨蛋 快退下
Carla, what are you going to do?
卡菈 你到底想干嘛
Is your underwear the latest style this year?
那套内衣 是不是今年最新款式
What are you talking about?
在说什么
Look at her expression. Cyclops full of question marks.
你看人家的表情 满脸独眼怪问号
Did you tell that?
你看出来了吗
It actually makes sense?
居然能通
Of course, I can tell that.
当然看的出来
That's the brand "Charm of Dwarves" of Miyako.
那是都心的品牌 "矮人之魅惑"
You've got good taste.
好有品味哦
Oh, you know it so well.
讨厌 你好懂哦
That's right. I'll fight with the vigilante in the village ahead later.
没错 之后我要跟 前方村落的义警打一架
So it's underwear battle.
原来是决胜内衣啊
-All right. Men, wait by the side. -It's a must to wear pink clothes in spring.
-好了 男性去旁边等 -春天就是要穿粉红色
-Now it's girls' talk. -It looks good on you.
-现在是女子聊天会 -好适合你哦
Is this how the underwear battle to be?
决胜内衣是这样用的吗
Thanks to Carla for distracting her. We're safe...
多亏卡菈分散她的注意力 才能平安…
Right. Safe...
对 平安…
There was no enthusiastic battle that made us nervous and sweaty.
没有让人紧张到冒手汗的热血战斗
No, there wasn't even a dispute.
不 甚至是一点争执都没有
Sorry, I'm more capable than a certain vanguard.
抱歉 我比某个前卫还要能干
Stop it.
别说了
By the way, where's the monster?
对了 那只魔怪呢
Anyway, I exchanged contact details with her.
总之 我先跟她交换联络方式
Let's go shopping next time.
下次我们一起去逛街吧
Your negotiation ability is surprisingly high.
你的交涉能力意外的高呢
It doesn't matter. You have to be healed quickly.
这不重要 你得快点疗伤
How? Do you want to use the correct healing magic?
怎么 你要使用正确的疗愈魔法吗
She's a healer, after all. It's normal, isn't it?
她是僧侣 这么做很正常吧
You protected me just now...
刚才你保护了我…
No. It's important to heal you first.
不 先疗伤要紧
I'll leave it to you.
拜托你了
You're too loud!
吵死了
Do you have to be so serious?
有必要这么认真吗
Geez!
可恶啊
Hold on! Stop! Stop it now!
等等 停 给我停一下
And don't exaggerate!
还有 不要这么夸张
Achoo!
哈揪
Stop it!
住手啊
What? I'm trying to heal you. Why did you ask me to stop?
干嘛啦 人家正努力帮你疗伤 干嘛叫人家停止
I'm angry.
森七七哦
Nonsense. Who would use healing magic and yell at the same time?
废话 哪有人边施展疗愈魔法 边鬼吼鬼叫的
And what does "Achoo" mean?
还有"哈揪"是什么意思
There's no choice. I'll be serious now.
真拿你没办法 我认真来吧
So what were you doing?
那你刚才在干嘛
Ryoko, can you get me a cloth?
灵子 能帮我拿块布吗
Carla, here you are.
卡菈 请
Ryoko has completely become an item box.
灵子完全变成道具箱了
That's because Ryoko has high storage skills.
因为灵子的收纳技能很高
Thank you for your compliment.
谢谢夸奖
Is it counted as storage?
这能算收纳吗
What are you going to do with this cloth?
你拿这块布要干嘛
Just watch.
看着就是了
It's ordinary cloth.
这是普通的布
Cover the wound.
覆盖在伤口上
Transfer power to it.
传送能量过去
Count to three and remove the cloth.
数到三后 拿开布
It's almost the same as before.
跟刚才几乎一样啊
You really don't know how to count down.
你真的不懂什么是倒数耶
What? The swelling goes down.
什么 手消肿了
My skin is shiny and elastic.
皮肤既有光泽又有弹性
Is this a magic trick?
变魔术吗
Power of hands.
双手能量
That's amazing!
很厉害耶
Am I be surprised or something?
该说我很意外还是什么呢
What are you talking about?
突然说什么呢
Seeing you use normal healing magic,
看到你使用普通的疗愈魔法
I wonder if it's normal.
我在想这样算不算普通
Do you think I can't use magic normally?
你以为我不会正常使用魔法吗
It's been like this so far.
至今为止都是这样啊
So you always think I'm a girl full of maternal intellect and love.
所以一直以来你只觉得 我是个充满母性知性和爱的女孩
Oh, my.
唉唷讨厌
I don't think so.
我没这么觉得
But to be honest, you're incredible.
但老实说 你很厉害
Your magic skills seem really strong.
魔法技能似乎真的很强
You have a bad personality, though.
虽然个性很烂
Over there.
在那
-I'm still a starless adventurer -Over there.
-我都到这个年纪了 -在这
-at my age. -Geez.
-却还是个无星冒险家 -可恶
Other adventurers even called me a veteran rookie.
甚至被别的冒险家说 是万年菜鸟
But recently, I suddenly feel like I'm getting along with a freak like you.
但最近 我突然觉得 自己跟你这种怪人很合得来
Over there.
在那
If you were an ordinary and serious person, you would have formed a party with others.
如果你是普通认真的人 早就跟别人组队了
And I'd continue to fight alone.
而我则是会继续单打独斗
Don't run.
别跑
I'm often attacked mentally by you, though.
虽然经常受到你的精神攻击
Well... How should I put it...
那个…怎么说呢…
-Anyway... -Don't run.
-总之… -别跑
-Thank you. -Don't run. Don't run.
-谢谢你 -别跑别跑
I'm looking forward to working with you.
以后还请多指教
How strange. Where does she go?
奇怪 跑哪去了
Please don't thank me so seriously.
请别这么认真的感谢我
And... And I should be...
而 而且 偶才素…
Thanks for forming a party with me.
感瞎泥 愿意跟偶租队
Well... That...
就素 那锅…
You should thank me well.
好好感谢我
That's what's annoying.
就是这样让人不爽
It's about time to leave.
差不多该出发了
Help!
救命啊
Help...
救命…
I'm the village head of the dwarves.
我是矮人族的村长
Dark Wizard Dolman.
黑暗魔导士多尔曼
I attacked the village to get the imperial body of the village.
为了得到村里的御神体 而攻击了村子
The world will be destroyed if the imperial body is taken away by Dolman.
御神体被多尔曼抢走的话 世界就会毁灭
A hero full of courage.
充满勇气的勇者啊
Please stop Dolman. I'll leave it to you.
请阻止多尔曼吧 拜托了
My grandfather is the village head.
我爷爷是村长
He asked me to give the letter to someone who looks gentle.
要我把信交给看起来很温柔的人
Then he let me run away.
就让我逃走了
All the villagers have been caught.
村子里的人都被抓起来了
Please rescue them all.
拜托 请救救大家
Speaking of Dolman, he's the villain who led the artificial army group.
说到多尔曼 他可是率领了 人造士兵军团的大坏蛋
Dolman.
多尔曼
I've heard about him.
我曾听过传闻
Five stars, no...
五星 不…
He has very powerful magic power.
他拥有非常强大的魔力
Zero-star Alvin with bracket laugh may not be able to beat him.
零星括号笑的埃尔文 应该赢不了他吧
NEXT EPISODE PREVIEW "FINALLY, IT COMES TO THE LAST EPISODE. THANK YOU FOR WATCHING TILL NOW. INCLUDING THE STAFF OF"
(下集预告) (终于到了最后一集 感谢大家收看到现在)
"THE ORIGINAL WEBSITE, WE'D LIKE TO EXPRESS OUR SINCERE THANKS TO YOU." Wow, we were asked to read the preview.
(包括原著网页的工作人员们一同向大家献上诚挚地道谢) 哇 被叫来念预告了
"SINCE THERE'S NO FINAL ENDING IN THE ORIGINAL WORK," Because the next episode is the last episode.
(因为原著中尚未出现最后结局的内容 所以这集几乎是原创) 因为下集是最后一集
"THIS EPISODE IS ALMOST ORIGINAL. BUT THE CONTENT IS ALSO FROM THE ORIGINAL AUTHOR, TANNEN NI HAKKOU." Oh, yeah?
(但内容也是来自原著作者丹念发酵老师) 是哦
"THE LINES AND INSPIRATION OF DWARF CHARACTERS" Don't you know that?
(设计的矮人角色台词和灵感) 你不知道吗
"ARE DESIGNED TO INTEGRATE THE CONTENTS BEFORE AND AFTER." We'll be knocked down by the enemy
(努力把前后内容都统整起来) 被敌人打倒
"FINALLY, WE CAN REST ASSURED. BUT IT'S LONELY TO END LIKE THIS." and aced.
(终于可以放心了 但就这样结束真令人感到寂寞) 然后灭团
"HOPEFULLY, CARLA AND ALVIN CAN CONTINUE TO GET ALONG." No way!
(希望卡菈和埃尔文能继续相处) 不会吧
"AND THE ORIGINAL STORY ISN'T OVER YET. PLEASE CONTINUE TO SUPPORT IT." Please look forward to it.
(而原著的故事还没结束 请务必继续支持) 大家敬请期待
"THANK YOU VERY MUCH FOR WATCHING. THANKS AGAIN SINCERELY." I'm looking forward to it.
(非常感谢大家的收看 再次献上真诚地感谢) 好期待哦
"THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR EPISODE TWELVE, "FINAL EPISODE"." Please stay tuned!
(真的非常谢谢大家的第十二话"最后一集") 大家要看哦
"STAY TUNED." We seem a little serious...
(要继续观看哦) 好像有点认真…